This is a 3.
It's sloppily written and rendered at an extremely low resolution of 28x28 pixels,
but your brain has no trouble recognizing it as a 3.
And I want you to take a moment to appreciate how
crazy it is that brains can do this so effortlessly.
I mean, this, this and this are also recognizable as 3s,
even though the specific values of each pixel is very different from one
image to the next.
The particular light-sensitive cells in your eye that are firing when you
see this 3 are very different from the ones firing when you see this 3.
But something in that crazy-smart visual cortex of yours resolves these as representing
the same idea, while at the same time recognizing other images as their own distinct
ideas.
But if I told you, hey, sit down and write for me a program that takes in a grid of
28x28 pixels like this and outputs a single number between 0 and 10,
telling you what it thinks the digit is, well the task goes from comically trivial to
dauntingly difficult.
Unless you've been living under a rock, I think I hardly need to motivate the relevance
and importance of machine learning and neural networks to the present and to the future.
But what I want to do here is show you what a neural network actually is,
assuming no background, and to help visualize what it's doing,
not as a buzzword but as a piece of math.
My hope is that you come away feeling like the structure itself is motivated,
and to feel like you know what it means when you read,
or you hear about a neural network quote-unquote learning.
This video is just going to be devoted to the structure component of that,
and the following one is going to tackle learning.
What we're going to do is put together a neural
network that can learn to recognize handwritten digits.
This is a somewhat classic example for introducing the topic,
and I'm happy to stick with the status quo here,
because at the end of the two videos I want to point you to a couple good
resources where you can learn more, and where you can download the code that